<resources>
    <string name="app_name">SeahawkTours</string>
    <string name="select">SELECT</string>
    <string name="cis">CIS Building</string>
    <string name="hoggard">Hoggard Hall</string>
    <string name="deloach">DeLoach Hall</string>
    <string name="bear">Bear Hall</string>
    <string name="dobo">Dobo Hall</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string-array name="building_names">
        <item></item>
        <item>CIS Building</item>
        <item>Hoggard Hall</item>
        <item>DeLoach Hall</item>
        <item>Bear Hall</item>
        <item>Dobo Hall</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="cis_info">The Computer Information Systems (CIS) building was constructed to house the Information Systems and Operations Management Department from the Cameron School of Business and the Department of Computer Science from the College of Arts and Sciences. The CIS Building, a new 51,731 square-foot state-of-the-art facility on the UNCW campus, opened January 10, 2007 for the new school semester. Work on the facility began on July 29, 2004 with the groundbreaking, and competed in December of 2006. The building cost approximately $12.8 million and was funded by the North Carolina State Bond campaign of 2000.
    Housed within the new building is the Financial Markets Room and, thanks to a donation from Edward Jones and over 50 if its financial advisers, the Edward Jones Financial Lab. Both rooms contain a stock board and ticker, however the Edward Jones Financial Lab also includes the Bloomberg Trading Terminal. With this terminal, students and faculty have the ability to trade stocks directly with the New York Stock Exchange, NASDAQ and more.
    The Department of Computer Science and the Department of Information Systems and Operations Management are housed at CIS together and are jointly offering a Master of Science in Computer Science Information Systems (MSCSIS) degree, an intensive graduate program aimed at preparing the student to assume leadership roles in the development and implementation of computer and information systems.</string>
    <string name="hoggard_info">Hoggard Hall was one of the three original buildings built at the current campus location in 1961. It initially housed classrooms for Biology, the Computing Center and Lab, Office of Institutional Research and Nursing School Laboratories. Currently, the School of Nursing, Office of Computing and Information Services, and Academic Affairs Offices occupy Hoggard Hall. In 2005, Hoggard Hall was expanded to include the Technology Assistance Center (TAC). It remains an architectural focal point for the UNCW campus along with the cannon and flagpole commons.
    Dr. John Hoggard had a long and varied life. He was born in Aulander, North Carolina and completed his undergraduate studies at Wake Forest University. After earning his medical degree from Medical College of Virginia, Dr. Hoggard practiced in Aulander, Atkinson and later Wilmington. Dr. Hoggard served in the Spanish-American War attached to Teddy Roosevelts regiment in Cuba. He also completed a tour of duty during World War I. Dr. Hoggards numerous business interests included; founder of Toms Drug Company, director of Cooperative Savings and Loan Bank and as well as one of the organizers of the Morris Plan Bank, which later became Bank of Wilmington. He held the position of Chairman of the Board of Education in New Hanover County from 1935 to 1952 when Wilmington College emerged under the control of this Board. Dr. Hoggard delivered the first commencement address to the graduates of class of 1949. Later, Dr. Hoggard served as the second president of Wilmington College from 1949 to 1958. He established the Hoggard Medal of Achievement Award given to the student showing the most improvement during their years at UNCW. After retiring as president, Dr. Hoggard continued to serve the college on the Board of Trustees until his death in 1965. Hoggard Hall stands as a tribute to his many contributions in the development of this campus.</string>
    <string name="deloach_info">Originally called the Physics-Chemistry Building, this structure housed classrooms for those departments. Groundbreaking took place in July of 1967, occupation began in 1968, with the official renaming ceremony to DeLoach Hall in October of 1985. Currently the building holds offices and classrooms for the Department of Physics, Department of Physical Oceanography and the Department of Earth Sciences. The Department of Chemistry was housed here until Dobo Hall opened. DeLoach Hall contains a large teaching auditorium and several laboratories.
        Dr. Will DeLoach was born in Alabama in 1910. He received his BS/MS from Samford University (Howard College of Arts and Sciences) and his doctorate in Chemistry from the University of Chicago in 1939. During World War II, Dr. DeLoach served as a first lieutenant with the United States Public Health Services where he studied the use of DDT in malaria control. He arrived at Wilmington College in 1963 as the first doctoral-holding chemistry professor. He also held the position of Chairman of the Chemistry Department until he retired in 1976. Among his numerous academic achievements was recognition by the American Chemical Society in 1972. Through his generous financial support UNCW awards a scholarship to an outstanding student in chemistry as well as supports the Will S. DeLoach Distinguished Professor of Chemistry Chair. Dr. DeLoach was given professor emeritus status in 1978. His legacy of academic commitment remains in the building that bears his name.</string>
    <string name="bear_info">Bear Hall opened at its present site in 1972 as the home for the Business and Economics Departments. Currently, the Departments of Computer Science, Mathematics and Statistics, and Philosophy and Religion occupy classrooms, teaching labs and faculty offices. The College of Arts and Science also resides here. As the inscription on the plaque states Bear Hall is named for, The original Isaac Bear Building, located at Market and 13th Streets, served as the first home of Wilmington College, outside the public school system. Classes were first held there in 1947. Constructed in 1912, the name of the first building was given by Samuel Bear, Jr. (1854 to 1916) as a memorial to his brother, Isaac Bear. The Bear family, owners of an intrastate wholesale dry goods firm located on Front Street, made a number of large donations to better the community such as a wing to James Walker Memorial Hospital. Isaac Bear was known as one of Wilmington\'s most capable and highly esteemed businessmen. He was a member of North State Lodge of BNai Brith, past Grand President of District Grand Lodge, and B.P.O.E Elks 532. Upon his death, the Isaac Bear Memorial School served to remember the close friendship and devotion between the brothers and their interest in public welfare. The Order of the Isaac Bear is an honorary organization composed of faculty members that taught at the site of the original Wilmington College. Once the college built the new campus off of College Road, the Isaac Bear Building was torn down (1961).</string>
    <string name="dobo_info">Opened for use in 1996, the New Science Building contained classrooms, laboratories and faculty offices for the Chemistry and Biology Departments. Known as Dobo Hall since its 1999 dedication to the Dobo brothers, it is currently used by the Department of Biology and Marine Biology and the Department of Chemistry. As both native sons and alumni of Wilmington College the brothers Dobo made their mark on the local community. Gabriel William (Bill), a World War II veteran came to the newly opened college in 1948 and wrote a column for the Seahawk newspaper. Robert (Bob) Ridgely, also a veteran on World War II, attended Wilmington College in 1950. After completing their studies, the brothers established two private water companies - Cape Fear Utilities and Quality Water Supplies, which contributed to the growth of New Hanover County. Their businesses were sold to the City of Wilmington in 1999. As philanthropists, their generosity has sustained UNCW and other educational and humanitarian institutions throughout the state. The building\'s plaque inscription reflects their benevolent dedication, "The future of southeastern North Carolina is brighter as a result of their commitment to their hometown, Wilmington College and the University of North Carolina at Wilmington." Bob Dobo passed away April 28, 2009.</string>
    <string name="cis_link">
        For more information, please visit &lt;a href="https://library.uncw.edu/web/collections/archives/bnl/cis.html">https://library.uncw.edu/web/collections/archives/bnl/cis.html&lt;/a>.
    </string>
    <string name="hoggard_link">
        For more information, please visit &lt;a href="https://library.uncw.edu/web/collections/archives/bnl/8.html">https://library.uncw.edu/web/collections/archives/bnl/8.html&lt;/a>.
    </string>
    <string name="deloach_link">
        For more information, please visit &lt;a href="https://library.uncw.edu/web/collections/archives/bnl/2.html">https://library.uncw.edu/web/collections/archives/bnl/2.html&lt;/a>.
    </string>
    <string name="bear_link">
        For more information, please visit &lt;a href="https://library.uncw.edu/web/collections/archives/bnl/19.html">https://library.uncw.edu/web/collections/archives/bnl/19.html&lt;/a>.
    </string>
    <string name="dobo_link">
        For more information, please visit &lt;a href="https://library.uncw.edu/web/collections/archives/bnl/25.html">https://library.uncw.edu/web/collections/archives/bnl/25.html&lt;/a>.
    </string>
    <string name="about_string">
        Created by Alex Bolsoy. UNCW building information and images courtesy of the UNCW &lt;a href="https://library.uncw.edu/archives_special/archives">University Archives&lt;/a>.
    </string>
</resources>
